LOVELLI FUAD

WRITER, ILLUSTRATOR, DATA SCIENTIST

EMAIL: lovelliariesti@yahoo.co.id PHONE: +62811838065 LOCATION: Jakarta, Indonesia

FACEBOOK: lovelli.fuad TWITTER: lovellifuad LINKEDIN: ariesti GITHUB: ariesti

SUMMARY

I am passionate about helping businesses take off and making sure businesses and workforces get healthier and more productive. I create content that provides insight on my area of consultancy, as well as valuables out of my hobbies and weekend projects, where I test websites, apps, digital products, tech gadget to provide feedback. I review products that are not books, too, but I'm keeping it to just fashion and food at the moment.

I am dedicated to partnering with innovators to discover if and how we can provide a better user experience for our products and services. I once completed a data science specialization course and currently I am taking classes on data visualization and data journalism. My qualifications include certifications on data science, responsive web design, digital marketing, arts and culture.

To sum up, I am a writer, editor, and enlightened illustrator who is now starting my own art practice under The Minimal Web.

EDUCATION

University of Indonesia

Bachelor's Degree, Faculty of Humanities, 2002

Coursera

Data Scientist, Data Science, 2014 Web Design, Responsive Web Design, 2017

Google Analytics Academy

Data Scientist, Google Analytics, 2016

Hubspot Academy

Inbound Marketing Certified, Digital Marketing, 2017

Google News Lab

Training, Data Journalism, 2017

EMPLOYMENT

Ariesti, Freelance writer and illustrator, Jakarta, Indonesia

Nov 2002 - Current

As a freelancer I take up projects in the areas of copywriting, creative writing, translation and interpretation, and tutoring.

Verbalizelt, Translator/Interpreter, New York, NY

Mar 2013 - Feb 2016

VerbalizeIt has recently been acquired by another startup. It is now called Smartling.

Rev Transcription, Transcriptionist/Captioner, San Francisco, CA

Nov 2015 - Mar 2016

SKILLS

ADOBE CREATIVE SUITE: Adobe Illustrator CC, Adobe Photoshop CC, Adobe Dreamweaver CC, Adobe InDesign CC DIGITAL ARTS: Processing, ArtRage, Digital Photography

WRITING & CONTENT: Feature Writing, Content Writing, Copywriting, Editing, Creative Writing, Blogging, Articles, Essay Writing DIGITAL MARKETING: Blogging, Inbound, Content Marketing

PROJECTS

The Minimal Web

Jan 2017 - Jan 2018

The Minimal Web is my take on starting an art practice. The idea was conceived after taking a few courses on Skillshare, and as a final or mid-term project I began compiling materials in-between my hours for the website. It is a work in progress that is planned to start taking off mid-2017.

The Freelance Spirit

Feb 2017 - Current

Exploring freelance work in Asia and the World, I have created and compiled materials to educate myself and others who would probably benefit from the knowledge. For example: the difference between "working from home" and "remote work", types of businesses for a beginning freelancer, etc.

AWARDS

Participant in Research Proposal Design Training, University of Indonesia

A group of selected lecturers were provided a chance to take part in this internal training and successful candidates were handed out certificates.

Gading News Award 2nd Place: News Category, The Jakarta Fashion & Food Festival

The Jakarta Fashion & Food Festival is an annual event held every May since 2006. I took part in 2008 as I was taking up a one-year journalism training with the Jakarta Post Training Department.

ACTIVITIES

The Freelance Spirit, Founder

Current

The Minimal Web, Founder/Illustrator

Current

My first project is to create an author website for myself. Currently this is the design and planning phase, with the soft launch date planned to be somewhere in March, 2017.

VOLUNTEERING

Translators Without Borders, Translator, Jakarta, Indonesia

Current

The Translators Without Borders is a response based volunteering program. Volunteers translate millions of words and help the organization run. Although the nature of the job is volunteering, a volunteer needs to be a professional translator or a native speaker to volunteer in a crisis response project.